(Leonard:)Now that I'm actually about to go out
with Penny, I'm not excited, I'm nauseous.
(Sheldon:)Then your meal choice is appropriate.
(Sheldon:)Starch absorbs fluid...
(Sheldon:)...which reduces the amount
of vomit available for violent expulsion.
(Howard:)- Right.
- You also made a grammatical mistake.
You said "nauseous"
when you meant "nauseated."
(Sheldon:)But go on.
(Leonard:)Sheldon, this date
is probably my one chance with Penny.
What happens if I blow it?
(Sheldon:)Well, if we accept your premise and also
accept the highly improbable assumption...
(Sheldon:)...that Penny is the only woman
in the world for you...
(Sheldon:)...we can logically conclude
that the result of blowing it...
(Sheldon:)...would be that you end up a lonely,
bitter old man with no progeny.
(Sheldon:)The image of any number
of evil lighthouse keepers...
...from Scooby-Doo cartoons
comes to mind.
(Leonard:)You're not helping.
All right, what response on my part...
(Sheldon:)...would bring this conversation
to a conclusion?
(Leonard:)Tell me whether or not
to go through with the date.
Schrödinger's cat.
(Leonard:)Wow, that's brilliant.